so that's why i decided to build
this project the
ai ops serverless platform which
the goal is to reduce the time
to the time to detect the
problem so the ai explain in a
plain english what caused this
problem so the engineer doesn't
have to go through logs to
decide what happened and go
through logs to figure out what
happened and to decide how to
to fix the problem because the
ai model for
amazon bad wars solves this
problem so he detect and
discover what caused the problem
and send the message through a
slack so the engineer received
the message with the explanation
where the ai explain everything
that caused this this specific
problem so this saved time for
we save a lot of time to the
engineer
when they are normally is
detected by
cloudwatch the event is rooted
through is rooted to event
bridge and step function and
ai model analyze the
problem the ai model through
amazon bedrock analyze the
problem and send this resume to
the engineer
so the goal of this platform is
to reduce the time of
detection so the platform has as
mission to analyze the
anomaly and after analyzing this
anomaly make a resume of this
anomaly what caused the
problem and how to fix the
problem and then send this
resume to through slack to the
engineer so the engineer receive
give the message and already
knows what caused this
problem so the engineer doesn't
have to go full logs to know
what caused this problem so the
goal is to reduce the time and
also to give full control to the
engineer to decide to decide if
the ai can solve this problem or
not and the engineer will have
two options to approve
or to not approve the
ai remediation so if the
engineer decide to approve the
the ai remediation the ai will
solve the problem in a question
of minutes so if the engineer
decide to not approve the
ai remediation so he can decline
this
proposition for this
project i chose many
aws services like cloudwatch
is the one who detected
problem and the event is rooted
through event bridge and step
function and after that the
problem as i said is analyzed by
ai model through
amazon bedrock that make the
analyze and detect the real
problem and also for
that i created four lambda
function that one of these
function is the remediation
function with
which the mission is to solve
the problem and many others
function also like the assistant
handbook which is mission is to
answer the question if the
engineer has any question on or
doubt about the so the aim of
this project is to help engineer
to understand and resolve the
problems and anomalies in
production in a question of
minutes so they can
solve this problem
them fast and also maintaining
the all control of any change
that happen in the
infrastructure so thank you for
watching in the next
video i'll be explaining more
about the services that i chose
and why i chose each
service thank you very much